Let us start on our Docker journey by learning what is Docker.
Docker is a containerization platform for building softwares,
something like a virtual machine without the use of external hardware.
Container virtualize the entire operating system of a machine to run multiple applications
on a single host OS.
Containers contain operating system like Linux, Windows or Mac OS.
Inside this OS there are other programs installed.
These programs can be .NET, Apache, engine X and so on.
In this figure we can see there is a Docker container and we have an operating system.
Ubuntu Linux installed on it.
.NET software is installed on the Ubuntu OS which as told earlier is running inside a Docker container.
We also have engine X steps server installed on Ubuntu OS.
So this means we have an OS with our needful programs.